<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Home on Plan Do Check</title>
    <link>https://pdq.pages.dev/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Home on Plan Do Check</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 01 Oct 2023 08:00:00 -0700</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://pdq.pages.dev/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Considerations about Active Directory</title>
      <link>https://pdq.pages.dev/posts/hardening/hardening/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Oct 2023 11:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pdq.pages.dev/posts/hardening/hardening/</guid>
      <description>Active Directory Privileged Access Introduction The challenge of understanding the access privileges of various groups in Active Directory. Often, the full impact of a group&amp;rsquo;s access is not fully comprehended by the organization. Attackers frequently exploit access, even if it&amp;rsquo;s not always privileged access, to compromise Active Directory. Components of Access Rights Active Directory group membership. AD groups with privileged rights on computers. Delegated rights to AD objects through modifications of default permissions (for security principals, both direct and indirect).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Detection Engineering</title>
      <link>https://pdq.pages.dev/posts/ttx/ttx/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Oct 2023 10:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pdq.pages.dev/posts/ttx/ttx/</guid>
      <description>Detection Engineering Building an effective detection engineering system requires time, a scope and an understanding of the signals analysis you desire to perform. You should conduct training and assessments of your detection engineering environment focusing on understanding the threat model for your organization. When you consider how you will calcuate &amp;lsquo;risk&amp;rsquo; I suggest that you use accessible language, this tool is focused on providing quantification and qualification of risk and even includes a random number generator to roll your chances based on 10,000 roles.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Functions</title>
      <link>https://pdq.pages.dev/tools/functions/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Oct 2023 10:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pdq.pages.dev/tools/functions/</guid>
      <description>Functions Functions Overview In the context of a structured process, various functions are performed to ensure the efficient execution of tasks. These functions are organized into different blocks representing specific phases. The following sections provide an overview of these functions within each block.
Block: Problem Identification and Change Initiation Function 1 (F1): Identify and Document the Problem
User (A) identifies and documents the problem (C) or the need for change (D).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blocks</title>
      <link>https://pdq.pages.dev/tools/building_playbook/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Oct 2023 08:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pdq.pages.dev/tools/building_playbook/</guid>
      <description>Blocks Block: Problem Identification and Change Initiation Task 1: User (A) identifies and documents the problem (C) or the need for change (D). Task 2: Work Role (B) reviews the problem (C) or change (D) request initiated by the User (A) and validates its significance and impact. Block: Change Control Record Creation Task 3: Work Role (B) creates a Change Control Record (F) and fills in the necessary details, including the problem (C) or change (D) description and the affected systems or processes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>User Guide for Graphical Representation</title>
      <link>https://pdq.pages.dev/posts/usergroups/containers/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Oct 2023 08:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pdq.pages.dev/posts/usergroups/containers/</guid>
      <description>User Guide for Graphical Representation This user guide provides an overview of a graphical representation created using the Mermaid library. The diagram visualizes the relationships and connections between various elements within a system, including an Active Directory structure, a Trouble Ticket Mapping System, Primary Work Role ID Mapping, and Relationship Mapping.
Active Directory The &amp;ldquo;Active Directory&amp;rdquo; is represented as a subgraph and contains a hierarchy of elements within it:
Root (A) is the top-level element.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Act</title>
      <link>https://pdq.pages.dev/posts/post-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Oct 2023 11:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pdq.pages.dev/posts/post-3/</guid>
      <description>This is where the rubber hits the road, and it&amp;rsquo;s your opprotunity to shine. Book a free no obligation call click here</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Do</title>
      <link>https://pdq.pages.dev/posts/post-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Feb 2023 10:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pdq.pages.dev/posts/post-2/</guid>
      <description>Evaluation/Improvement Phase (Steps 7-10) Step 7: Process Evaluation - Collect and analyze data on the execution of prevention activities. Step 8: Outcome Evaluation - Measure the impact of prevention activities on desired outcomes. Step 9: Continuous Quality Improvement (CQI) - Review data and past decisions to enhance prevention activities. Step 10: Sustainability for a Prevention Activity - Plan for the long-term sustainability of successful prevention activities. Follow these steps to effectively plan, implement, evaluate, and improve your prevention initiatives.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Plan</title>
      <link>https://pdq.pages.dev/posts/post-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Feb 2023 10:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pdq.pages.dev/posts/post-1/</guid>
      <description>Planning Phase (Steps 1 -6) Step 1: Assessing Problems and Resources - Identify and select priority problems for your prevention activity. - Understand the available resources. Step 2: Setting Goals and Desired Outcomes - Define a vision, goals, and specific outcomes for your prevention activity. Step 3: Evidence -Based and Promising Practices - Select prevention activities with evidence of effectiveness. Step 4: Assessing Fit for a Prevention Activity - Evaluate how well selected activities fit the target population, community, and mission.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Trouble Ticket</title>
      <link>https://pdq.pages.dev/posts/trouble-ticket/troubleticket/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Feb 2023 10:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pdq.pages.dev/posts/trouble-ticket/troubleticket/</guid>
      <description>Guide to System Engineering Process Introduction As a systems engineer, your role is crucial in ensuring the stability and reliability of complex systems. This guide will help you understand and navigate the system engineering process using the provided diagram as a reference.
1. Increasing the Time Between Failures The primary goal of a systems engineer is to increase the time between system failures. This can be achieved through the following strategies:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Control Families NIST and ISO</title>
      <link>https://pdq.pages.dev/tools/controlfamilies/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2023 08:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pdq.pages.dev/tools/controlfamilies/</guid>
      <description>Control Families Control families in information security standards like NIST SP 800-53 and ISO 27001 represent a structured approach to safeguarding critical assets and ensuring the confidentiality, integrity, and availability of sensitive information. These control families are essential for establishing and maintaining robust security practices within an organization.
NIST SP 800-53 Control Families Control Family Core Functions Cybersecurity Framework Components Access Control (AC) Manage and restrict access to information systems. Identification and Authentication (IA), System and Communications Protection (SC) Audit and Accountability (AU) Audit system activities and retain audit logs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>External Resources</title>
      <link>https://pdq.pages.dev/tools/external_resources/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2023 08:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pdq.pages.dev/tools/external_resources/</guid>
      <description>SKF Framework
OWASP SAMM
Binary Risk Analysis
Security Rat
Free Dev tools
Analyze Malicious Software
HoneyPots
Cybersecurity and Tools:
Untitled Goose Tool for Azure, Azure Active Directory, and Microsoft 365 Python Cheat Sheet Linux Command Line Cheat Sheet Quick Reference for ChatGPT Deep Learning Cheat Sheet Data Sources and Visualization: 6. Makeover Monday - Data 7. BFI Statistical Yearbook 8. Data.gov 9. Maven Analytics Data Playground 10. Knoema Infographics 11. Sons of Hierarchies - Real-World Fake Data</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Meeting Agenda</title>
      <link>https://pdq.pages.dev/tools/meeting_agenda/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2023 08:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pdq.pages.dev/tools/meeting_agenda/</guid>
      <description>This page serves as the template for technical meeting agendas, limit meeting sessions to 45 minutes, and technical conversations to not more than 3 per 45 minute period.
Meeting Agenda I. Introduction A. Welcome and introductions B. Purpose and goals of the meeting C. Agenda overview II. Review of Previous Action Items A. Recap of action items from the previous meeting B. Update on the progress of each action item C.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://pdq.pages.dev/posts/networkanalysis/networkanalysis/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pdq.pages.dev/posts/networkanalysis/networkanalysis/</guid>
      <description>I. Introduction Computer systems are connected, with networks. The network components are presented in seven layers, from physical to Application, layers are interconnected with systems built of components. This document will explains three concepts
Transport Layer Protocol vulnerabilities, controls and mitigations
Network Layer Protocols vulnerabilities, controls and mitigations
Media Access Control(MAC) vulnerabilities, controls and mitigations
OSI Layer Network Communication Stack Layer 7. Application Application Layer 6. Presentation Presentation Layer 5. Session Session Layer 4.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
